[Music]
all right happy Monday episode two of my
morning grind every morning I come in I
go through bis byell some of the other
listing websites to see what new
business listings came up either
yesterday evening or over the weekend so
today we're going to take a look I got a
request last week to look in St Louis
Missour so we'll see what we can find
okay St Louis Missouri all Industries
let's see what we can see uh feex routes
are really popular it's not my thing I'm
not sure how to even look into these
deals but there are definitely Pros out
there who specialize so I don't
typically look at restaurants
restaurants are a unique animal you know
if you are experienced in restaurants
you want to buy a restaurant then I
think that's great but um a lot of
people who are new to buying a business
that have never owned a restaurant
before restaurants are super risky I
don't know the restaurant space myself
that well so again there are Pros out
there who specialize in restaurants so
stuck on and masonry uh you know I like
I like home service businesses I like
construction
businesses uh asking price is a million
with a cash flow of 273 so I mean we're
already looking almost four times so
it's pretty high if someone was
specifically looking for a stuck own
masonry business I would probably look
into it but that uh multiple is just
really high long care business but it's
going to be too small for an SBA
loan thriving Outdoor Equipment company
for sale well I mean let's take a look
got some feedback that uh I should show
my math I couldn't figure out out a way
to make the calculator look nice or for
it to even make sense I built this
little
tool helps me helps me go faster so see
asking price of this
is
$2,430 total sales
6,695
621 iida earnings before
interest tax depreciation amateurz we
don't
have cash flow or
SD
609 so we'll consider this to be the S
the eida also eida is lower than SD but
if we don't have it we can make them the
same all right so let's see let's learn
a little bit about the business Outdoor
Equipment Company that specializes in a
wide range of essential equipment from
mowers snow equipment areator spreaders
seeders revenues above 6.5
million yeah profit over 600 telling us
what we
know high inventory half a million in
inventory equipment assets of
150,000 Management in place so you know
that's going to be important for us it
is SBA pre-approved that's really
important that means that they've had an
SBA lender look at this business they've
looked at the financials so as long as
you qualify U then this deal will have
no problem getting some SBA funding for
it diverse product line yeah residential
and Commercial customers it's great more
about the financials more about the
management fully operational season
management
okay so like we're kind of just a little
redundant here option to purchase or
lease real estate interesting okay so
there could be real estate in the deal
so it's not going to be included in
these numbers but real estate is
available for some creative financing
some people like to bring in an investor
to buy the real estate that they'll
lease it back from and they'll use that
to you know bundle the whole deal
together get the deal done okay so let's
take a look at the
math all right so over here on this
other screen we've got the asking price
2.4 million total sales
6.69 usually we want to see profit
margins of
of at least 20% 20% is like perfect uh
over 20% is is even better uh with
retail it can be a little bit different
you know when you're when you're
maintaining inventory you're selling
there's not a ton of margin in these
things um so you know really if a
business is between 10 and
20% I should make a third column here
make that yellow 10 to 20% could be
yellow under 10% is a problem uh over
20% is is
great so right now we're sitting at
99.1% so under
10% um not great there's some some Ro
room for improvement but the nice thing
is there is cash flow so there is
some resource there that you can use
whether it's you know adjusting your
pricing running more sales getting more
more deals cutting some overhead there's
opportunities uh this valuation multiple
is at the top of the Range four times uh
sde is the top of the range but it is
warranted when you have an absentee
owner situation so when you have a
business is just running on its own then
you know that's where you get that that
four times multiple and it sounds like
that's the case here uh 20 full-time
employees the seller is active but with
16 full time four part time time
management in place then uh you know I I
wonder what the seller is doing you know
that's something I'd want to want to
learn about okay debt coverage ratio so
the down payment amount is going to be
10% as it said in the listing SBA
pre-qualified
$243,000 down so your loan amount will
be
here uh 287
and we'll do that over 10% SBA Loans are
over 10 years unless real estate makes
up 51% then it could be over 25 years
but for this one we're going to do it
without the real estate so we're looking
at uh say
$28,900 per month pop this back in
here
okay so most lenders look for a debt
service coverage ratio the debt service
coverage ratio is how much you have in
monthly
profit left over after you pay your loan
payment so the loan payment amount is uh
28,000 almost 29,000 a month your
monthly cash flow is 50,000 little over
50,000 debt coverage ratio 1.76 so like
I said B Banks look for a debt coverage
ratio of 1.5 or more um some have
special rules the SBA says 1.15 some
banks would go 1.25 but you know by and
large most of your conservative lenders
are looking for uh 1.5 or better this is
1.76 which is why they they
pre-qualified it that's why the SBA
lender said that this was good to go
after you put your down payment of you
know
$243,000 and you earn your profit of
$609 in the first year you're looking at
you know 250% so you know you're you're
looking at 2.5 times your money so after
you put the down payment of
$243,000 and earn your first Year's
profit of 609 you're looking at 2.5
times your money in the first year that
is the year one cash on cash return on
your investment I like it this is a good
one this is a good business couple
things I want to look at I mean you know
you still got to talk to the seller talk
to the broker you know site visits look
at inventory all that stuff but but this
is one that's worth looking into
[Music]
paid social advertising Outreach 100%
retainer contracts 1.6 million marketing
businesses are are cool uh for a lot of
reasons I mean some people are looking
for like your boring businesses like car
washes and laundry mats I like
businesses that are web based or could
be web- based that you can have remote
staff there's just a ton of margin there
um it's
riskier but that's the whole point
buying an established business so we're
looking at a a paid social
advertising Outreach 100% customer
retainer contracts in St Louis Missouri
asking price is 1.6 million gross
revenue total sales is 2, 342,415
e but we do have the eida earnings
before interest tax depreciation and
amateurz 4 to
91 956 and SD is always higher than iida
because it includes the owner's
compensation this agency is a leading
player in the field of lead generation
specializing in paid social advertising
strategic cold Outreach with an
impressive track record they're renowned
for their unmatched expertise in
LinkedIn marketing I might buy this one
their team excels in crafting tailor
strategies that Empower businesses to
connect with their target audience
achieve sustainable growth by leveraging
paid social channels and strategic
Outreach agency delivers premium leads
and sales opportunities helping clients
achieve exceptional results they stand
out as a trusted partner for businesses
aiming to maximize their Roi and build
prosperous future in the digital
landscape 12year history in the industry
seller feels like he's reached his
personal limit and how he can grow
looking for a buyer who understands the
business is worth taking it to the next
level 16
employees so the agency it looks like it
operates physically two locations St
Louis and York oh St Louis division does
work remotely great okay weekly
Gatherings at a co-working space that's
cool the agency competes with several
agencies in different segments all right
yeah I mean there's a ton of competition
for Market for advertising but why start
when you can buy and then build they
didn't get at SBA
pre-qualified um that's okay you know
sometimes they you know if the business
is the right deal it'll still qualify so
you know $160,000 down 10% for SBA Loans
you're looking at a loan for 1.4
million over 10 years that's say roughly
10%
interest so your loan payment will be
$199,000 a month at asking price 1.6
million total sales 2.3
million the eida so not the sell's
discretionary earnings but the net
profit before interest tax depreciation
amateurz
$471,000 net profit over 20% so you know
the last review I I had this little
green for anything over 20% um it is
just over 20% so that's great you know
good margins for for the number of of
employees although maybe on the low side
for an agency I don't know maybe some
opportunity to increase prices or you
know add new services that are higher
margin services so lot to look into
there they do a lot of different things
in this Legion space but seems like
they're focused on LinkedIn so maybe
some niching opportunity the valuation
multiple is
3.4 little high you know I I think
something like this if the seller is
involved you know extensively which we
don't
know um maybe coming in and offering a
little bit less but you know all in all
you know 2.5 to three times you know
remote Workforce you know ability to to
scale I could see paying three times you
know I think that makes sense so it's
not something that would scare me away
it's it's within the range let's put it
that way the bank is going to love it
Deb service coverage ratio is two times
as long as the bank that you're talking
to who feels comfortable with a a web-
based business um having these retainer
contracts in place should help you're
looking at three times you know 3x in
your money in the first year so you put
$160,000 down you have this uh you know
the eida 471 th000 so about three times
cash on cash return in the first year I
joke that I I'd buy this um I would buy
this this is a good business I
definitely I don't know if I'd buy it
but I would definitely look into to it I
would uh I'd reach out to the broker
sign the NDA get more information
because this is this looks cool and uh
it's probably going to get some it's
probably get a lot of attention I
haven't looked at a lot in in St Louis
but there are a lot of really
interesting businesses a lot of diverse
businesses in St
Louis Legal Services that's cool it's
interesting more FedEx a lot of FedEx
routes for sale in St Louis all right
well I have a lot of work to do I'm
going to get back at it this is been uh
episode two take two of uh the morning
grind if you want me to look at
businesses in your area drop a comment
uh let me know where you want me to
search I'll pick them at random and see
what we can find
[Music]